Catalog of the Walt Whitman Literary Manuscripts in the Walt Whitman Collection, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley
Published by The Walt Whitman Archive in collaboration with the University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries.
- A Night Remembrance [I sit by the edge of the pond], 1878–1882; ucb.00070; xxx.00960; prose 1 leaf handwritten (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Various scraps of paper, including an envelope address to Whitman from Richard Maurice Bucke, which have been pasted together to create one large leaf. These scraps comprise an nearly complete, though not unrevised, draft of A Night Remembrance, first published in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ) and collected in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ). On the verso of this manuscript is what appears to be a scrap of a letter.
- This has been & is September and October wild flowers, 1878–1882; ucb.00071; xxx.00961; prose 3 leaves handwritten (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Notes on flowers that Whitman revised and used in Wild Flowers, which appeared in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ) and Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- Out of mere civility [Out of mere civility], 1878–1882; ucb.00072; xxx.00961; prose 1 leaf handwritten (Box 1, Folder 42)
  A heavily revised sentence, which Whitman revised even further before including in Wild Flowers, Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ). Whitman included Wild Flowers in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- A Civility too long neglected [?bring this in the text], 1878–1882; ucb.00073; xxx.00962; prose 1 leaf handwritten (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Notes which contributed to A Civility too Long Neglected, first published in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ), and included in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- Mature Summer Days and Nights [in the brook], 1878–1882; ucb.00074; xxx.00963; prose 2 leaves handwritten (Box 1, Folder 44)
  This manuscript is a draft of Mature Summer Days and Nights, first published in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ) and collected in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- Exposition Building—New City Hall—River Trip [visit to Exposition building &c &c], 1879–1882; ucb.00075; xxx.00964; prose 4 leaves handwritten (Box 1, Folder 45)
  A draft of Exposition Building—New City Hall—River Trip, first published in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ) and collected in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- Cloudy and wet, wind due east Sept. 3 '79—Cloudy and wet, about 1879; ucb.00076; xxx.00972; prose 2 leaves handwritten (Box 1, Folder 79)
  A draft of Swallows on the River, first published in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ) and collected in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- In the midst of the 22nd book for Sparrows, about 1882; ucb.00078; xxx.00972; prose 1 leaf handwritten (Box 1, Folder 81)
  Notes that contributed to Swallows on the River, first published in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ) and collected in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- Travelling the Rocky Mountains travelling the Rocky mountains, about 1879; ucb.00083; xxx.00804; prose 1 leaf handwritten (Box 1, Folder 87)
  Heavily revised prose notes detailing Whitman's trip over the Rocky Mountains in September 1879. Much of the material in this manuscript was revised and used in An Egotistical Find, first published in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ); and included, without revisions, in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- The wild carrot The Wild Carrot, 1878–1879; ucb.00098; xxx.00963; xxx.00924; prose handwritten 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 67)
  This manuscript consists of three smaller scraps of paper that have been pasted together to form a larger sheet. The first part of this manuscript was slightly revised and used nearly verbatim in Mature Summer Days and Nights. The second and third scraps were revised and contributed to Distant Sounds. Both of these prose pieces first appeared in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ), and were included in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- Denver Impressions Bullion—Hard Cash, about 1879; ucb.00084; xxx.00984; prose 1 leaf handwritten printed (Box 1, Folder 52)
  Notes on the gold and silver product, which contributed to Denver Impressions, Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ). Whitman included Denver Impressions in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- A Contralto Voice ['80—Sunday], 1880; ucb.00085; xxx.00985; prose 2 leaves handwritten (Box 1, Folder 53)
  A heavily revised and partially cancelled draft of A Contralto Voice, which first appeared in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ) and was collected in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- My Native Sand and Salt Once More July 25 '81—Far Rockaway LI, 1881; ucb.00086; xxx.00986; prose 4 leaves handwritten (Box 1, Folder 55)
  A draft of My Native Sand and Salt Once More, first published in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ) and included in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- Still, bright mellow forenoon [The Sky Monday], about 1876; ucb.00095; xxx.00820; prose 2 leaves handwritten (Box 1, Folder 64)
  Notes on the sky, dated 13 November 1876, and that contributed to The Sky—Days and Nights—Happiness, which appeared in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ) before being collected in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- Toronto...in the bookstore on king Sparrows—Swallows, about 1880; ucb.00077; xxx.00972; prose 1 leaf handwritten printed (Box 1, Folder 46)
  Notes that contributed to Swallows on the River, first published in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ), and collected in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- In all the manifold shows of the universe Sky, about 1878; ucb.00092; xxx.00820; prose 2 leaves handwritten (Box 1, Folder 61)
  A heavily revised draft on the "vastness" of the human soul. Portions of this manuscript were revised and used in The Sky—Days and Nights—Happiness, first published in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ), and collected in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).
- How cheap and common and unfailing (The Sky), about 1877; ucb.00099; xxx.00820; prose 1 leaf handwritten (Box 1, Folder 68)
  Notes, dated 14 July 1877, that contributed to The Sky—Days and Nights—Happiness, first published in Specimen Days & Collect ( 1882–1883 ), and collected in Complete Prose Works ( 1892 ).